MD. MOHON

Email: mdmohon6145@gmail.com
Phone: +8801782638193
Linkedin Github Portfolio

Address: Rajshahi, Bangladesh

SUMMARY

As a web development specialist, I have over one year of professional experience executing web application analysis, build-up, and Debugging. Notable achievements include boosting the conversation rate of an existing website by 100% with improved code and design.

SKILLS

Frontend: Html5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React.JS, Redux, Redax-saga, React-query

Backend: Node.JS, Express.JS, MongoDB, Mongoose, JWT, REST Api

Tools: Git, Bitbucket, Npm, Visual Studio, Webstrom, google cloud Platform, Firebase, Jira, Figma

WORK EXPERIENCES

SUN IT LIMITED (Rajshahi, Bangladesh)

Frontend Developer(Intern) | 01 November, 2021 - 30 April 2022

- Developed the client-facing core React application and implement features as needed.
- Implemented quality code to make the application more stable and maintainable

Mangrove Software and IT (USA Based)

Software Developer | 01 November, 2022 - Current

- Here I am working as a full-stack developer based on MERN Stack.
- I build a UI by React.js in Frontend and create a backend API endpoint in Node.js
- Here I have to complete all aspects of UI and backend.

PROJECTS

E-Tutors (Full-Stack) Live Site Frontend Code Backend code

(16 Sep 2022 - 24 Oct 2022)

- I have built a learning management system called E-Tutors using React, Bootstrap, Node.JS, Express.JS, MongoDB, and Cloudinary.
- Both students and teachers can use this system, but there will be some feature differences between them.
- From here, students can find tutors for their specific subjects and check their preparation through online tests.

The Cycle House (Full-Stack) Live Site Frontend Code (12 Nov 2021 - 19 Nov 2021) Backend code

- The user will be able to purchase any bicycle from this website and he will have to login to purchase.
- If the admin enters this website with anything other than the admin email and password, he will not be able to see the admin dashboard.
- I create this website in Full MERN Stack Focused.

Varendra IT (Full-Stack) (01 Sep 2022 - 25 Oct 2022) Live Site

- Varendra IT is a Computer Traning Center. Here training is given in many subjects of the computer.
- This website is basically created to know all the information and all the updates related to our Varendra
 it

EDUCATION

Diploma in-Engineering | 2019 - Running

Rajshahi Polytechnic Institute - Computer Science Engineering

LANGUAGES

- Bangla (Native)
- English (Proficient)
- Hindi (Proficient)